Guide to the Dorothy Porter Wesley Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series II. Professional Papers, 1869-2003
  - Writings, 1928-1995
    - Writings by Dorothy Porter Wesley
      - Book Review of Theodore Parker by Henry Steele Commager, 1937- (Box 162, Folder 1420)
      - Book Review of Two Quaker Sisters. From the original diaries of Elizabeth Buffum Chace and Lucy Buffum Lovell., 1937- (Box 162, Folder 1421)
      - Boston Women Candidates for Rediscovery (draft), 1937- (Box 162, Folder 1422)
      - "Books with Negro Characters for Children", 1937- (Box 162, Folder 1423)
      - A Catalogue of the African Collection in the Moorland Foundation Howard University Library edited by Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1958- (Box 163, Folder 1424)
      - A Catalogue of Books in the Moorland Foundation Compiled by Workers on Projects 271 and 328 of the Works Progress Administration Margaret R. Hunton and Ethel Williams, Supervisors Dorothy B. Porter, Director, 1939- (Box 163, Folder 1425)
      - Catalogue of the Charles L. Blockson Afro-American Collection Edited by Charles L. Blockson, foreword by Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1990- (Box 163, Folder 1426)
      - Collections on the American Negro: A List of References, Undated (Box 163, Folder 1427)
      - Data Concerning the Writings and and Professional Activities of Dorothy Porter Wesley, Undated (Box 163, Folder 1428)
      - "David Ruggles, An Apostle of Human Rights", 1943- (Box 163, Folder 1429)
      - The Dictionary Catalog of the Jesse E. Moorland Collection, Undated (Box 163, Folder 1430)
      - A Directory of Negro Graduates of Accredited Library Schools compiled by the Columbia Civic Library Association (including Dorothy Porter Wesley) 1900-1936, 1937- (Box 163, Folder 1431)
      - "Documentation on the Afro-American: Familiar and Less Familiar Resources", 1969- (Box 163, Folder 1432)
      - Dorothy Porter Wesley's bibliography of published and unpublished writings, 1993- (Box 163, Folder 1433)
      - "Dorothy Burnett Porter Wesley: Enterprising Steward of Black Culture" by Avril Johnson and Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1994-1995 (Box 163, Folder 1434)
      - "Early American Negro Writings: A Bibliographical Study", 1945-1946 (Box 163, Folder 1435)
      - "Early American Negro Writings: A Bibliographical Study", 1945-1946 (Box 164, Folder 1436)
      - "Early Manuscript Letters Written by Negroes", 1939- (Box 164, Folder 1437)
      - Evidences of Religious Activity of Black Women in Anti-Bellum America, 1993- (Box 164, Folder 1438)
      - "Family Records, A Major Resource for Documenting the Black Experience in New England", 1973- (Box 164, Folder 1439)
      - "Fiction by African Authors: A Preliminary Checklist", 1962- (Box 164, Folder 1440)
      - "Fifty Years of Collecting", 1984- (Box 164, Folder 1441)
      - "First International Congress of Africanists", 1963- (Box 164, Folder 1442)
      - Genealogy: A Brief List of References, 1973- (Box 164, Folder 1443)
      - George Washington Williams (1849-1891), 1971- (Box 164, Folder 1444)
      - "A Glimpse of Negro History", 1953- (Box 164, Folder 1445)
      - Hannah Kilham (Box 164, Folder 1446)
      - Historical and Biographical Data of Phillis Wheatley's Publication (article and draft), 1973- (Box 164, Folder 1447-1449)
      - "Howard University", 1967- (Box 165, Folder 1450)
      - Howard University Masters' Theses, 1946- (Box 165, Folder 1451)
      - "Howard University: A Selected List of References" compiled by Dorothy Porter Wesley and Betty Jo Lanier, 1965- (Box 165, Folder 1452)
      - Empty, Undated (Box 165, Folder 1453)
      - Instruments of Scholarships, Undated (Box 165, Folder 1454)
      - Leaves and Vacations, 1935- (Box 165, Folder 1455)
      - "The Librarian and the Scholar: A Working Partnership", 1965-1967 (Box 165, Folder 1456-1457)
      - "A Library on the Negro", 1938- (Box 165, Folder 1458)
      - "Library Sources for the Study of the Negro", 1936- (Box 165, Folder 1459)
      - List of Books on the Negro, Undated (Box 165, Folder 1460)
      - Literary Societies (draft), 1994- (Box 165, Folder 1461)
      - Literature for Children With Negro Characters, Undated (Box 165, Folder 1462)
      - "Literature Pertaining to the American Negro", 1935- (Box 165, Folder 1463)
      - Literary Scene in Latin America: Selected References, 1945- (Box 165, Folder 1464)
      - Maria Louise Baldwin, (1856-1922) (drafts), 1968- (Box 165, Folder 1465-1467)
      - Monroe Nathan Work, Undated (Box 165, Folder 1468)
      - The Moorland Foundation, 1946- (Box 166, Folder 1469)
      - The Moorland Foundation Library of Negro Life and History Located at Howard University, Undated (Box 166, Folder 1470)
      - The Negro in American Cities, A Selected and Annotated Bibliography, 1967- (Box 166, Folder 1471-1473)
      - "The Negro in the Brazilian Abolition Movement", 1952- (Box 166, Folder 1474)
      - The Negro Collection in Print at Howard University, Undated (Box 166, Folder 1475)
      - Negro Culture (Excerpt in the Progressive Education), 1935- (Box 166, Folder 1476)
      - The Negro in the United States, 1968-1975 (Box 166, Folder 1477-1478)
      - "Negro Women in Our Wars", 1944- (Box 166, Folder 1479)
      - "New Books for Children's Book Week", 1938- (Box 166, Folder 1480)
      - "Northeastern Brazilian Novelists", 1955- (Box 166, Folder 1481)
      - "The Organized Educational Activities of Negro Literary Societies, 1828-1846", 1936- (Box 166, Folder 1482)
      - "The Organized Educational Activities of Negro Literary Societies, 1828-1846", 1936- (Box 167, Folder 1483)
      - Our Man Nell (draft), 1995- (Box 167, Folder 1484)
      - Outline Plan for Teaching a course on the Library and its Books to College Freshman, 1928- (Box 167, Folder 1485)
      - "Padre Domingos Caldas Barbosa: Afro-Brazilian Poet", 1951- (Box 167, Folder 1486)
      - "Phylon Profile, XIV: Edward Christopher Williams", 1947- (Box 167, Folder 1487-1489)
      - Preface to "A Checklist of Afro-American Art and Artists", 1970- (Box 167, Folder 1490)
      - "The Preservation of University Documents: With Special Reference to Negro Colleges and Universities", 1942- (Box 167, Folder 1491)
      - A Proposal for the Establishment of a Committee on Howard University Archives, Undated (Box 167, Folder 1492)
      - "Recent Literature on the Negro", 1940- (Box 167, Folder 1493)
      - "Recorded Evidences on the Practice of Medicine", Circa 1922 (Box 167, Folder 1494)
      - Reminiscenes of Mordecai Johnson, 1990- (Box 168, Folder 1495)
      - "The Remonds of Salem: A Nineteenth Century Family Revisited", 1986- (Box 168, Folder 1496)
      - A Report on the need for a Union Catalog of Printed Works on the Negro, 1968- (Box 168, Folder 1497)
      - Research Centers and Sources for the Study of African History, 1960- (Box 168, Folder 1498)
      - Role of the Negro Collection in Teaching and Research at Howard University (draft), 1967- (Box 168, Folder 1499)
      - "A Selected Bibliography of Bibliographies on the Negro ", Undated (Box 168, Folder 1500)
      - "Selected List of Books by and About the Negro", 1936-1940 (Box 168, Folder 1501)
      - Selected List of References about African American Collections, 1971- (Box 168, Folder 1502-1503)
      - "Slavery Bitterly Contested by Citizens who set up Underground Stations Here", 1954- (Box 168, Folder 1504)
        - Oversize, 1954- (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1596)
      - "Sojourner Truth Calls Upon the President: An 1864 Letter", 1972- (Box 168, Folder 1505)
      - "Some Books Featuring Negro Characters for Young Children", 1937- (Box 168, Folder 1506)
      - "A Special Library on the Negro", 1938- (Box 168, Folder 1507)
      - Empty, Undated (Box 168, Folder 1508)
      - The Water Cures, 1954- (Box 168, Folder 1509)
      - The William O. Brown Collection, 1969- (Box 168, Folder 1510)
      - "Women Activists, Wives, Intellectuals, Mothers, and Artists", 1975- (Box 168, Folder 1511)
      - A Working Bibliography on the Negro in the United States, 1968- (Box 169, Folder 1512-1517)
      - "Your's for Breaking Every Yolk: Selected Writings and Speeches of William Cooper Nell, 1833-1874", 1992- (Box 169, Folder 1518)
      - Unidentified Writings, 1966-1973 (Box 169, Folder 1519)
      - Unidentified Writings, 1966-1973 (Box 170, Folder 1520)
      - Notes, Crica 1952-1973 (Box 170, Folder 1521-1524)
    - Writings about or in Dedication of Dorothy Porter Wesley
      - A Biographical Profile of Distinguished Black Pioneer Female Librarians compiled by Lelia G. Rhodes, 1983- (Box 171, Folder 1525)
      - "A Brief Study of Mrs. Dorothy Burnett Porter: From Birth to Completion of High School 1905-1922" by Janice M. Muganda, 1972- (Box 171, Folder 1526)
      - "Dorothy Porter Wesley: A Bio-Bibliographic Profile" by Helen H. Britton, 1994- (Box 171, Folder 1527)
      - "Dorothy Porter Wesley, Curator Extraordinaire" by Karen L. Jefferson, 1990- (Box 171, Folder 1528)
      - "The Energy-Charged Life of Dorothy Porter Wesley" by Harriet Jackson Scarupa, 1990- (Box 171, Folder 1529)
      - "Essay: From Stereotype to Archetype" by Patricia J. Williams, 1993- (Box 171, Folder 1530)
      - Ethnic Collections in Libraries Edited by E.J. Josey and Marva L. DeLoach, (Dedication to Dorothy Porter Wesley), 1983- (Box 171, Folder 1531)
      - "An Important Figure in Black Studies: Dr. Dorothy Porter Wesley" By Maurice A. Lubin, 1973- (Box 171, Folder 1532)
      - "Library's African American Resources to be Symposium Focus" by Helen Dalrymple, 1994- (Box 171, Folder 1533)
      - "Moorland-Spingarn Research Center: A Past Revisited, A Present Reclaimed" by Michael R. Winston, 1974- (Box 171, Folder 1534)
      - Notable Black American Women Edited by Jessie Carney Smith, article by Esme Bhan, 1992- (Box 171, Folder 1535)
      - "Profile of a Collector: Dorothy B. Porter Wesley" by Esme Bhan, 1990- (Box 171, Folder 1536)
      - "Public University and Private American Library Holdings on the Negro" by Ernest Kaiser, 1969- (Box 171, Folder 1537)
      - Recent Notable Books: A Selected Bibliography in Honor of Dorothy Burnett Porter compiled by Morland Spingarn Research Center staff, 1974- (Box 171, Folder 1538-1539)
      - Reference Aids in Black Studies published by G.K. Hall Reference Books, Undated (Box 172, Folder 1540)
      - "A Wealth of African American Resources: Scholars' Use of LC Collections Inspires Seminar" by Charlynn Spencer Pyne, 1994- (Box 172, Folder 1541)
      - Unidentified Writings, Circa 1993-1995 (Box 172, Folder 1542)
      - Clippings about Dorothy, Circa 1929-2000 (Box 173, Folder 1543-1549)
        - Oversize, Circa 1950-1996 (Box 179, Folder 1597-1598)
          Clippings
    - Writings by James A. Porter
      - The American Negro Artist Looks at Africa, 1960- (Box 174, Folder 1550)
      - Untitled Writings, Circa 1937-1960 (Box 174, Folder 1551)
    - Writings by Charles H. Wesley
      - Afro-American Encyclopedia, Introduction by Charles H. Wesley, 1972- (Box 174, Folder 1552)
      - Richard T. Greener, Introduction for Exhibition Catalogue (draft), 1980- (Box 174, Folder 1553)
      - Selected Titles on Afro-American and African Culture. Chairman's Message by Charles H. Wesley, 1969- (Box 174, Folder 1554)
    - Writings by Constance Porter Uzelac
      - Bueno Excursion, 1947- (Box 174, Folder 1555)
      - "Moving a Fragmented Collection", 1969- (Box 174, Folder 1555)
      - Milan Properties, Realtors, Inc. (advertisement), Undated (Box 174, Folder 1555)
      - Unidentified writings, Undated (Box 174, Folder 1555)
    - Writings by Others
      - Writings by Others, Circa 1920-1994 (Box 174, Folder 1556-1558)
      - Writings by Others, Circa 1920-1994 (Box 175, Folder 1559-1564)
      - Writings by Others, Circa 1920-1994 (Box 176, Folder 1565-1571)
      - Writings by Others, Circa 1920-1994 (Box 177, Folder 1572-1577)
- Series III. Research Files, 1847-2004
  Research Files is organized into five subseries: African Literature and Culture; African American Literature and Culture; Caribbean and South American Literature and Culture; Remond Family research; and William Cooper Nell research.
  Research Files consists of clippings, drafts, photostat reprints of letters and notes documenting the research conducted by Dorothy Porter Wesley, Constance Porter Uzelac and Charles Harris Wesley. Materials include research on African, African American, Afro-Caribbean, and Afro-Latino literature and culture used for building the Moorland Spingarn Collection as well as Dorothy Porter Wesley's bibliographies, published books and articles including Afro-Braziliana: A Working Bibliography (1978), Early Negro Writing, 1760-1837 (1971), and William Cooper Nell, Nineteenth-Century African American Abolitionist, Historian, Integrationist: Selected Writings 1832-1874 (2002). Articles on Sarah Parker Remond, Charles Lenox Remond and their families written by Dorothy Porter Wesley are also included. Dorothy Porter Wesley's second husband, historian and author Charles Harris Wesley's notes and drafts for William Cooper Nell, Nineteenth-Century African American Abolitionist, Historian, Integrationist: Selected Writings 1832-1874 (2002), are also contained in the series. Other writings include notes and illustrations by Constance Porter Uzelac who completed the bibliography on William Cooper Nell, Nineteenth-Century African American Abolitionist, Historian, Integrationist: Selected Writings 1832-1874 (2002) in 2002. The series also contains clippings, correspondence and writings on Alain Leroy Locke, professor at Howard University, as well as the correspondence and catalog books of Arthur Barnette Spingarn, who collected African American books, newspapers and manuscripts and whose collection formed the basis of the Moorland Spingarn Collection at Howard University.
  - African Literature and Culture, 1928-1973
    Dorothy Porter Wesley visited West African countries such as Ghana, Nigeria, Senegal and the Ivory Coast to collect Africana materials for the Moorland-Spingarn Research Center. Wesley also worked as an acquisitions librarian at the National Library of Nigeria, a position she received as part of a Ford Foundation grant from 1962-1964. The African Literature and Culture research subseries consists of bibliographies, notes, clippings and articles documenting Wesley's experience in West Africa.
    - "Abolition and African Political Thought" by George Shepperson, Circa 1963 (Box 186, Folder 1599)
    - African authors, 1960-1963 (Box 186, Folder 1600-1608)
    - "African Countries and Islands Adjacent to Africa" compiled by the Moorland Foundation, 1956-1961 (Box 187, Folder 1609)
    - African cultures, 1935-1966 (Box 187, Folder 1610)
      - Oversize, 1958- (Box 274, Folder 2533)
    - African fashions, 1963-1968 (Box 187, Folder 1611)
      - Oversize, 1966-1968 (Box 274, Folder 2534)
    - African history checklist, 1962- (Box 187, Folder 1612)
    - African library materials, 1960-1965 (Box 187, Folder 1613)
    - African Literature, 1945-1965 (Box 187, Folder 1614-1617)
    - African Studies Association, 1967- (Box 187, Folder 1618)
    - "America in the Niger Valley" by A.H.M. Kirk Greene, 1962- (Box 187, Folder 1619)
    - American Society of African Culture Newsletter, 1964-1965 (Box 187, Folder 1620)
    - Amina, Queen of Zazzau, Undated (Box 187, Folder 1621)
    - Anthologies, Circa 1960 (Box 187, Folder 1622)
    - "Arabic documents of Northern Nigeria" by A.D.H. Bivar, 1959- (Box 187, Folder 1623)
    - Arabic names, Circa 1960-1962 (Box 188, Folder 1624)
    - Basutoland, Circa 1960 (Box 188, Folder 1625)
    - "Bibliography of Nigerian Fiction in English From the Doctoral Dissertation of Nancy J. Schmidt", 1965- (Box 188, Folder 1626)
    - Bills and receipts, 1962-1966 (Box 188, Folder 1627)
    - Books for Africa, 1960-1963 (Box 188, Folder 1628)
    - Book Reviews, Circa 1960-1967 (Box 188, Folder 1629)
    - "The Collection of Swahili Literature and its Relation to Oral Tradition and History" by J.W.T. Allen, 1959- (Box 188, Folder 1630)
    - "The Concept of an African Prose Literature" by Wilfred H. Whiteley, 1962- (Box 188, Folder 1631)
    - The Conference of African Writers by Randolph Vigne, 1959- (Box 188, Folder 1632)
    - "Contemporary African Negro Literature" by Miriam G. Koshland, 1956- (Box 188, Folder 1633)
    - "The Creative Writer of African Descent" by Miriam G. Koshland, 1956- (Box 188, Folder 1634)
    - Documents Inc., catalog, Undated (Box 188, Folder 1635)
    - Drama, Circa 1960 (Box 188, Folder 1636)
    - Folklore, Undated (Box 188, Folder 1637)
    - "French Influences on Leopold Senghor's Theory of Negritude" by Jacques Louis Hymans, 1928-1948 (Box 188, Folder 1638)
    - Ghana notes, Circa 1972 (Box 188, Folder 1639)
    - "Jacobus Eliza Johannes Capitein 1717-47" by F.L. Bartels, 1959- (Box 188, Folder 1640)
    - The Journal of Modern African Studies, reviews, 1965- (Box 188, Folder 1641)
    - Literary magazine, Undated (Box 188, Folder 1642)
    - Literature, 1962- (Box 188, Folder 1643)
    - Literature History and Criticism of Africa, 1964- (Box 188, Folder 1644)
    - "The Literature of British Central Africa" by George Shepperson, 1958- (Box 188, Folder 1645)
    - Location code for use in Nigerian Bibliography, Undated (Box 188, Folder 1646)
    - The Lovedale Press, Undated (Box 188, Folder 1647)
    - Luganda, 1962- (Box 189, Folder 1648)
    - Maps, Undated (Box 189, Folder 1649)
      - Empty, Undated (Box 189, Folder 1650)
    - Meeting on Libraries and Documentation, 1962- (Box 189, Folder 1651)
    - Modern African Writers (AMSAC), Undated (Box 189, Folder 1652)
    - Negro author catalog, 1928-1967 (Box 189, Folder 1653-1655)
    - "Negritude in West Africa" by Abioseh Nicol, 1960- (Box 189, Folder 1656)
    - Nigeria, 1943-1964 (Box 189, Folder 1657)
    - Nigerian authors, 1965- (Box 189, Folder 1658)
    - Nigerian literature and publications, 1964- (Box 189, Folder 1659-1661)
      - Oversize, 1944-1964 (Box 274, Folder 2535)
    - Nigerian printers and booksellers, 1958- (Box 189, Folder 1662)
    - Northern Rhodesia and Nyasaland, 1949-1961 (Box 190, Folder 1663)
    - "Onitsha Market Literature" by Donatus I. Nwoga, Undated (Box 190, Folder 1664)
    - Philip Butcher, lists, 1967- (Box 190, Folder 1665)
    - A Preliminary Bibliography of the Literature of Nationalism in Nigeria by Ruth Perry, 1956- (Box 190, Folder 1666)
    - "A Preliminary Bibliography of the Yoruba Language" compiled by F. Adetowun Ogunsheye, 1963- (Box 190, Folder 1667)
    - "Poems Guerriers Rwanda" by A. Coupez and Th. Kamanzi, 1962- (Box 190, Folder 1668)
    - Sierra Leone, 1973- (Box 190, Folder 1669)
    - "The Social and Econimic Background of Portuguese Negro Poetry" by Alfredo Margarido, 1962- (Box 190, Folder 1670)
    - South Africa, 1936-1958 (Box 190, Folder 1671)
    - Southern Rhodesia African Literature Bureau, 1960-1962 (Box 190, Folder 1672)
    - Time and attendance records, 1967- (Box 190, Folder 1673)
    - Title Index to Africa Report, 1960- (Box 190, Folder 1674)
    - Zulu literature (notes), Undated (Box 190, Folder 1675)
    - Notes, Circa 1960-1969 (Box 190, Folder 1676-1678)
    - Notes, circa 1960-1969 (Box 346, Folder 3059-3062)
  - African American Literature and Culture, 1797-2011
    The African American Literature and Culture research subseries consists of clippings, notes, and writings documenting the research conducted by Dorothy Porter Wesley for collection development in the Moorland-Spingarn Research Center. The subseries contains materials about and belonging to writer, philospher and educator Alain Locke including correspondence and writings. Materials belonging to Civil Rights leader and collector Arthur Barnette Spingarn, including correpondence and book catalogs can also be found in the subseries. Research and drafts for Early Negro Writings, 1760-1837 (1971) written by Dorothy Porter Wesley is also included.
    The subseries is organized into two groupings: General Research Files, and Early Negro Writings.
    - General Research Files
      - Abbie Mitchell Concert, Undated (Box 191, Folder 1679)
      - African American Authors, Undated (Box 191, Folder 1680)
      - Afro-American Newspapers, 1910-1974 (Box 191, Folder 1681)
      - Alice Werner, Circa 1943 (Box 191, Folder 1682)
      - Alain Leroy Locke Papers
        - Afro-American Page, 1912- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2536)
        - Bibliography of the Writings of Alain Leroy Locke, Undated (Box 191, Folder 1683)
        - Correspondence, 1920-1952 (Box 191, Folder 1684)
        - Death, 1954- (Box 191, Folder 1685)
        - Extract from the Annual Report, 1956-57 of the Moorland Foundation Howard University Library, 1957- (Box 191, Folder 1686)
        - Guide to the Alain L. Locke Papers prepared by Wilda Logan Willis, 1985- (Box 191, Folder 1687)
        - Last will and testament, 1945-1950 (Box 191, Folder 1688)
        - Manuscript Letters, Undated (Box 191, Folder 1689)
        - Memorandum, 1913-1915 (Box 191, Folder 1690)
        - The New Negro Thirty Years Afterward published by The Howard University Press, 1955- (Box 191, Folder 1691)
        - Notorized Inventory Art Collection Estate of Alain Leroy Locke, 1956- (Box 191, Folder 1692)
        - Organizations, Undated (Box 191, Folder 1693)
        - Photographs, Undated (Box 191, Folder 1694)
        - Writings about Alain Leroy Locke, Circa 1911-1970 (Box 191, Folder 1695)
        - Writings by Alain Leroy Locke
          - Negro Art Past and Present, 1937- (Box 191, Folder 1696)
          - "With Brush and Chisel: The Negro as Artist", Circa 1951 (Box 191, Folder 1697)
        - Notes, Undated (Box 191, Folder 1698)
        - Ephemera, 1957- (Box 191, Folder 1699)
      - American Negro Academy, 1979- (Box 192, Folder 1700)
      - American Negro Historical Society, 1881-1904 (Box 192, Folder 1701-1702)
      - American Negro Writers Biographical Data, Circa 1862-1895 (Box 192, Folder 1703)
      - Anna J. Cooper, 1972- (Box 192, Folder 1704)
      - Arthur Barnett Spingarn
        - Arthur Barnett Spingarn Collection Value, Circa 1947-1955 (Box 192, Folder 1705)
        - Correspondence, 1925-1979 (Box 192, Folder 1706-1707)
        - The Crisis, 1972-1980 (Box 192, Folder 1708)
        - Estimated budget for the expansion of library resources in the Negro Collection, Circa 1959 (Box 192, Folder 1709)
        - Howard University Bulletin, 1948- (Box 192, Folder 1710)
        - Negro Authors (list), Undated (Box 192, Folder 1711)
        - Parke-Bernet Galleries Inc., catalog books, 1966-1970 (Box 193, Folder 1712-1714)
        - A Transcript of a Tape-Recorded Interview with Arthur B. Spingarn, conducted by John Britton of the Civil Rights Documentation Project, 1968- (Box 193, Folder 1715)
        - Notes about Arthur B. Spingarn, Circa 1944-1981 (Box 193, Folder 1716-1717)
          - Oversize, 1981- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2537)
        - Clippings, Circa 1964-1981 (Box 193, Folder 1718)
          - Oversize, 1981- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2538)
      - Bessie Coleman, 1976- (Box 194, Folder 1719)
      - Bethume Museum, 1989- (Box 194, Folder 1720)
      - The Black Church, Circa 1937-1979 (Box 194, Folder 1721-1723)
      - The Black Church, 1976-1979 (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2539)
      - Black Studies Programs
        - Art, notes and clippings, 1976-1977 (Box 194, Folder 1724)
        - Black curriculum, 1969- (Box 194, Folder 1725)
        - Black integration, 1967-1968 (Box 194, Folder 1726)
        - Black integration, 1967-1968 (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2540)
        - Book shop and dealer notices, Undated (Box 194, Folder 1727)
        - California black studies, Undated (Box 194, Folder 1728)
        - National Evaluative Conference in Black Studies, 1971- (Box 194, Folder 1729-1730)